<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: widget | Adventures in code land]]></title>
  <link href="http://dominicphillips.de/blog/categories/widget/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dominicphillips.de/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-17T14:01:38+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://dominicphillips.de/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dominic Phillips]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Third Party Javascript & Widgets]]></title>
    <link href="http://dominicphillips.de/blog/2014/02/02/writing-third-party-widgets/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-02T13:13:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://dominicphillips.de/blog/2014/02/02/writing-third-party-widgets</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In this post I want to share some of the experience I picked up from building the <a href="http://www.stylight.co.uk">STYLIGHT</a> looks widget and third party javascript in general. Our widget allows users to embed looks (think of a collection of images, products and videos) into their own websites. Third party js is hard and there are lots of very annoying restrictions, bugs, and security concerns, after all you don&rsquo;t want to break peoples sites.</p>

<p>Third party widgets are all over the web, e.g. google analytics, disqus, all social share buttons and I expected to easily find best practices, ressource and blog posts on how to actually build quality, scalable widgets. But, quite the contrary, the only real helpful information I found was from a book by developers from disqus. I&rsquo;d definetely check it out if you&rsquo;re looking into writing third party js. <a href="http://thirdpartyjs.com/">Get it here</a>.</p>

<p>This is how our widget currently looks like:</p>

<center>
<a href="http://www.stylight.de/kayture/Looks/Blue-in-shanghai/" class="stylight-look" data-width="640"></a>
</center>




<div class="info">
  Third-party JavaScript is independent client code executing on a publisher's website, but served from a remote web address. It's used in the creation of highly distributed web applications, from social widgets, to analytics trackers, to full-featured embedded applications.
</div>


<p>Our widget is pretty simple but requires a lot of markup and styling, thats why I decided to inject it into the publishers site via an simple iframe, instead of fiddling with the DOM directly. This ensures that my JS and CSS is scoped to my iframe and I won&rsquo;t mess up the publishers site by accident. Another added benefit is that we also avoid the same origin restrictions this way.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Looks&rdquo; have variable heights so we need a way to communicate with the publishers &ldquo;document&rdquo; from within our iframe, to set its height accordingly. There is <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/window.postMessage">window.postMessage</a> but unfortunately it&rsquo;s not avaiable to all browsers.</p>

<div class="info">
  The window.postMessage method safely enables cross-origin communication. Normally, scripts on different pages are allowed to access each other if and only if the pages that executed them are at locations with the same protocol (usually both http), port number (80 being the default for http), and host (modulo document.domain being set by both pages to the same value). window.postMessage provides a controlled mechanism to circumvent this restriction in a way which is secure when properly used.
</div>


<p>I found <a href="http://easyxdm.net/">easyXDM</a> to be the perfect library to handle this problem. It uses postMessage and falls back to other methods like flash or FrameElementTransport, its a great little library which is also used by the &ldquo;big boys&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Next follows some pseudo code: First we set up a socket on the hosts site. Notice how the onMessage function uses the incoming &lsquo;message&rsquo; to change the iframes height. EasyXDM will inject an iframe into the specified container using the remote property as its src, which is really neat.</p>

<p>``` coffeescript Host</p>

<p>new easyXDM.Socket</p>

<p>  remote: &ldquo;<a href="http://your_iframe">http://your_iframe</a>&rdquo;</p>

<p>  container: document.getElementById &ldquo;container&rdquo;</p>

<p>  onMessage: (message, origin) &ndash;></p>

<pre><code>this.container.getElementsByTagName("iframe")[0].style.height = message + "px"
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<p>One socket wouldn&rsquo;t make much sense so we create a second one in our embedded iframe for a full fledged messaging system.</p>

<p>``` coffeescript Embedded Iframe</p>

<p>socket = new easyXDM.Socket</p>

<p>  onReady: &ndash;></p>

<pre><code>socket.postMessage document.body.scrollHeight
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<p>Rendering, analytics calls and added functionality all happen in our own &lsquo;domain&rsquo;, we just briefly touch the publishers DOM.
How do we make the widget configurable? One way is to ask the user to add an html element to her site which containns all options as data attributes, which we can then use as query / hash params for our iframe src. We may also use this element as our iframes container, WIN/WIN. I&rsquo;m by no means an experts but feel free to write comments in case you have any questions.</p>

<script>(function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0];if(d.getElementById(id))return;js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src='//d336s8nt4p00c3.cloudfront.net/widget/widget.js';js.async=true;fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);})(document,'script','stylight-wjs');</script>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
